<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Motivation on Sohan&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>http://sohanchy.github.io/blog/tags/motivation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Motivation on Sohan&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2016 Sohan Chowdhury, all rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://sohanchy.github.io/blog/tags/motivation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I have a Javascript allergy and hate its popularity so much.</title>
      <link>http://sohanchy.github.io/blog/journal/Why-I-have-a-Javascript-allergy-and-hate-its-damned-popularity/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://sohanchy.github.io/blog/journal/Why-I-have-a-Javascript-allergy-and-hate-its-damned-popularity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is 2016, and if you aren&amp;rsquo;t aboard the Javascript bullet train,  you aren&amp;rsquo;t doing it right.&lt;br /&gt;
I am writing this mostly as a rant, and this isn&amp;rsquo;t written for JS Ninjas, its for people like me who are coming to JS from C++, Java,etc and feeling very confused and lost.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.imgur.com/DwFCt8l.png&#34; alt=&#34;enter image description here&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a world where we proud ourselves in creating something in HTML5+JS,
that runs on a modern quad-core system while delivering the
performance that existed on 16-bit or even 8-bit systems with less
than 10 MHz CPU&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ndash; well in this world JS is going to stick around
for a long time. And I fear things are going to get much shittier than
this.  - Redditor /u/narancs&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The explosion of JS in both front-end and back-end has forced me to start trying to learn the damn thing. Even though I&amp;rsquo;ve been acquainted with JS for some time now, my past feeling  towards it resembled something along the lines of a skin allergy that causes itching in the whole body.
Before you bring out your chainsaws written in Node.js and cut me in half before I can even react.js, let me explain myself first.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many of javascripts simplest designs are very counter intuitive and can be very confusing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;var x = &amp;quot;5&amp;quot;;
x = x + 1;
console.log(x);    // x is 51
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You may be thinking, hey you dumbass, you initialized x as a string.
Of course it concatenated.
Well now lets try,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;var x = &amp;quot;5&amp;quot;;
x = x - 1;
console.log(x);    // x is 4
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Basically the + operator treats it as a string, while the - operator typecasts it into a integer and subtracts.
This is just wonderful and not confusing at all!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In javascript,
You can declare global variables inside functions, by mistake.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;function doStuff()
{
   x = 5;  // x is now a global variable
}

doStuff();

console.log(x);    //outputs 5
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you pass a variable to a function and change it, it will change only within the function.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;function addFive(x)
{
    x = x + 5;
}

var num = 4;
addFive(num);
console.log(num);    //output is 4;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Expected, right?
But&amp;hellip; if you pass an object, it is automatically passed by reference, and any change done inside is also changed on the outside.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;function addFive(x)
    {
        x.value = x.value + 5;
    }
var num = {};
num.value = 4;

addFive(num);
console.log(num.value);    //output is 9
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And guess what, you can&amp;rsquo;t pass a variable by reference even if you want to. What is the solution? Convert it to a object, pass it, do stuff, then again change it back to a variable.
That&amp;rsquo;s Just. Freaking. Awesome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first thing almost every guide says is that Javascript is an object oriented programming(OOP) language,
If you already have experience with C++/Java or some other OOP language, you might be thinking WoHoo!
But stop, don&amp;rsquo;t be so happy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;JS is OOP alright, but there&amp;rsquo;s a strong possibility that its not exactly what you are expecting&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What most people understand by Object Oriented Programming is this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You have Classes, they are like blueprints.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Classes have objects, like blueprints have Cars.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Classes can inherit other Classes and add stuff.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even though each car can have different colors, different speeds, etc; they still have the same blueprint, only their implementation changes. If a car blueprint does not have wings in it, a car made from that blueprint can not have wings. Common sense right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NOPE. What you are thinking about is Class based OOP,
But Javascript is a &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/JavaScript/Guide/Details_of_the_Object_Model#Class-based_vs._prototype-based_languages&#34;&gt;Prototype based OOP language&lt;/a&gt;,
In fact, it&amp;rsquo;s the only popular or widely used language that uses Prototype based OOP.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This means that in Javascript, &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/JavaScript/Guide/Working_with_Objects#Objects_and_properties&#34;&gt;there are no Classes&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All you have is objects. And objects are made from functions or other
objects.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Objects inherit other objects and add stuff to them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Objects made from the same parent object can have different&lt;br /&gt;
members, different functions, and these can be added to any distinct
object on the fly and without any effect on other objects of
the same type.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Basically, a car is not made from a blueprint, but it&amp;rsquo;s made from another car. And even though many cars are created from the same parent car, one of them can have wings and another may have 9 wheels instead of 4.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do you still feel that &amp;ldquo;Wohoo&amp;rdquo; ?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Objects can be objects and objects can be functions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;var x = [41];
var y = function(){
//do some stuff
return 41;
};

var z = function(){
//do some stuff
return 41;
}();

console.log(x);    //shows Array [ 41 ]
console.log(y);    //shows function y()
console.log(z);    //shows 41
console.log(y());  //shows 41
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know this also exists in some other languages, but that doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean I have to like the kind of readability problems and unpredictable
debugging horrors it can bring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can go on and on about things like these, but I won&amp;rsquo;t. Halfway through writing this, I googled and found many blogs written by people much more knowledgeable than me, pointing out a lot of the issues I have with JS and many many more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my opinion, Javascript is a shitty nonsense language. It should have died sometime between 2004 to 2006 and it should have been replaced with something much much better, but it wasn&amp;rsquo;t.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But since dreams are only dreams, it didn&amp;rsquo;t die, and instead became more widely used,  Javascript obviously must have it&amp;rsquo;s place.
And what I can only hope is that:
&amp;gt; Javascript - when used with the understanding of how ridiculous it is - can become a extremely useful tool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And if you are in the same boat as me, you should stop your whining, head over to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/JavaScript/Guide&#34;&gt;MDN JS Guide&lt;/a&gt;, and get on board the JS train as soon as you can, because this shit is here to stay, and it wont be going away any soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prologue</title>
      <link>http://sohanchy.github.io/blog/journal/prologue/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://sohanchy.github.io/blog/journal/prologue/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I started poking around HTML since I was in 7th grade.
I wanted to make my own web pages so I was snooping around Google to see how that was possible. The first few lines of HTML that I wrote were most probably a link with a a:hover effect, When I opened my page on a browser and the mouseover effect worked, I remember being excited like the little kid I was, and even showing my brother what I had accomplished. I really started having fun when I started learning php and jquery,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What started out as a curiosity turned into me typing away at my keyboard hours on end, night would come, bedtime would pass and I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t even notice.
I had to kill off my coding interests from grade 10 through 12 because of  the way our education system is. Everything, the future of your life basically depends on these 4 grades and you have to kill anything else but study from your mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which I tried to do but still didn&amp;rsquo;t succeed in becoming one of the BUET,CUET,&amp;hellip;IAN&amp;rsquo;S.
Yeah, in that sense, I am a failure. But whatever, IDGAF. At least not anymore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Benjamin Franklin said &amp;ldquo;Some people die at 25 and aren&amp;rsquo;t buried until 75.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People search for a passion all their life. I think I have found mine. So I&amp;rsquo;m going to try my best to pursue it. I&amp;rsquo;m getting back to doing stuff that I actually have an interest in.
I&amp;rsquo;m learning more low level languages, starting with C. Brushing up my rusted Web Development skills. Trying to stay focused, and waiting to see where that takes me. :)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>